

ANNELISE N. SMITH UX DESIGN & RESEARCH

253-682-7193 // annelisesmithux@gmail.com // anoelles.github.io

SKILLS

User Research
Usability Testing
Persona Development
Ethnography
Card Sorting
Journey Mapping
Content Analysis
HTML/CSS
Paper Prototyping
Mobile Experience Design
Axure
Sketch
InVision
OmniGraffle
Adobe Illustrator

EDUCATION

UX Design Immersive (2016) General Assembly Seattle

MA in Human Development (2013)

Washington State University Prevention Science Track

BA in Social Sciences (2011)

Washington State University Minors in German and Ethnic Studies

SUMMARY

I am a UX designer and researcher with experience in studying human behavior and motivation using both qualitative and quantitative approaches. Armed with a creative and analytical mind, I have a knack for identifying and incorporating users' needs at all steps of the design process. I am especially interested exploring user experiences with voice recognition and smart home technologies.

EXPERIENCE

UX Designer // Dive Around the Clock // Seattle, WA // Aug 2016 - Oct 2016

Improve alignment of website with user and organization needs through user research including interviews, usability testing, and behavioral observation; utilize IA principles and develop site maps/wireframes to enable intuitive navigation and increase click-through to donation and volunteer sign-up tasks; create copy and style guide

Field Marketing Specialist // Publicis Hawkeye // Seattle, WA // Oct 2015-Aug 2016

Devise, organize, and execute guerrilla marketing campaigns to drive product awareness and foster brand loyalty

Investigator // WA Child Protective Services // Tacoma, WA // Aug 2014- Oct 2015

Use motivational interviewing to identify core family problems and make critical decisions based on conflicting information in high-stress situations, complete forensic interviews to be submitted as evidence in court, design solutions using existing family and community resources; create accurate documentation in compliance with federal and state mandates.

Site Coordinator // Communities in Schools // Lakewood, WA // Aug 2013- Oct 2014

Collaborate with student, family, school, and community stakeholders to identify core needs and secure resources for at-risk students.

Research Assistant // Washington State University // Pullman, WA // Aug 2011- July 2013

Coordinate data collection and analysis for a 2-year NIH funded randomized control trial; collaborate as author on scholarly publications; write research briefs and literature reviews to support evidence-based decision making; develop outcome evaluation plans for existing health promotion programs; design, implement, and evaluate social media campaigns for incoming students.